[
	{
		"topicId": 1,
		"topicName": "HTML",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 1,
		"question": "HTML Stands for _____________?",
		"options": [
			"Hyper Text Makeup Language",
			"Hyper Text Markup Language",
			"Hyper Tech Markup Language",
			"None of these"
		],
		"answer": "Hyper Text Markup Language"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 1,
		"topicName": "HTML",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 2,
		"question": "HTML is considered as _________ language?",
		"options": [
			"Higher Level Language",
			"Markup Language",
			"OOP Language",
			"Programming Language"
		],
		"answer": "Markup Language"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 1,
		"topicName": "HTML",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 3,
		"question": "HTML markup language is a set of Markup ___________?",
		"options": [
			"Tag",
			"Attribute",
			"Groups",
			"Sets"
		],
		"answer": "Tag"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 1,
		"topicName": "HTML",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 4,
		"question": "HTML tags are used to describe document ___________?",
		"options": [
			"Definition",
			"Language",
			"Content",
			"None_ of these"
		],
		"answer": "Content"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 1,
		"topicName": "HTML",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 5,
		"question": "HTML Document can contain ______________.?",
		"options": [
			"Attributes",
			"Tags",
			"Plain Text",
			"All of these"
		],
		"answer": "All of these"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 2,
		"topicName": "CSS",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 1,
		"question": "Which of the following selector matches a element based on its id?",
		"options": [
			"The Id Selector",
			"The Universal Selector",
			"The Descendant Selector",
			"The Class Selector"
		],
		"answer": "The Id Selector"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 2,
		"topicName": "CSS",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 2,
		"question": "Which of the following property is used to control the repetition of an image in the background?",
		"options": [
			"background-color",
			"background-image",
			"background-repeat",
			"background-position"
		],
		"answer": "background-repeat"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 2,
		"topicName": "CSS",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 3,
		"question": "Which of the following property is used to align the text of a document?",
		"options": [
			"text-indent",
			"text-align",
			"text-decoration",
			"text-transform"
		],
		"answer": "text-align"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 2,
		"topicName": "CSS",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 4,
		"question": "Which of the following property is used to capitalize text or convert text to uppercase or lowercase letters?",
		"options": [
			"text-indent",
			"text-align",
			"text-decoration",
			"text-transform"
		],
		"answer": "text-transform"
	},{
		"topicId": 2,
		"topicName": "CSS",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 5,
		"question": "Which of the following property of a table element specifies the width that should appear between table cells?",
		"options": [
			"border-collapse",
			"border-spacing",
			"caption-side",
			"empty-cells"
		],
		"answer": "border-spacing"
	},	
	{
		"topicId": 3,
		"topicName": "JAVASCRIPT",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 1,
		"question": "Is JavaScript a case-sensitive language?",
		"options": [
			"True",
			"False",
			"xxx",
			"xxx"
		],
		"answer": "True"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 3,
		"topicName": "JAVASCRIPT",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 2,
		"question": "Which of the following type of variable is visible only within a function where it is defined?",
		"options": [
			"global variable",
			"local variable",
			"Both of the above.",
			"None of the above"
		],
		"answer": "local variable"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 3,
		"topicName": "JAVASCRIPT",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 3,
		"question": "Which of the following function of String object extracts a section of a string and returns a new string?",
		"options": [
			"slice()",
			"split()",
			"replace()",
			"search()"
		],
		"answer": "slice()"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 3,
		"topicName": "JAVASCRIPT",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 4,
		"question": "Which built-in method sorts the elements of an array?",
		"options": [
			"order()",
			"changeOrder(order)",
			"sort()",
			"None of the above."
		],
		"answer": "sort()"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 3,
		"topicName": "JAVASCRIPT",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 5,
		"question": "Which of the following function of Array object creates a new array with the results of calling a provided function on every element in this array?",
		"options": [
			"push()",
			"join()",
			"pop()",
			"map()"
		],
		"answer": "map()"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 4,
		"topicName": "BOOTSTRAP",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 1,
		"question": "Which of the following class styles a table with borders surrounding every element and rounded corners around the entire table?",
		"options": [
			".table",
			".table-striped",
			".table-bordered",
			".table-hover"
		],
		"answer": ".table-bordered"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 4,
		"topicName": "BOOTSTRAP",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 2,
		"question": "Which of the following class is required to be added to form tag to make it inline?",
		"options": [
			".inline",
			".form-inline",
			".horizontal",
			"None of the above"
		],
		"answer": ".form-inline"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 4,
		"topicName": "BOOTSTRAP",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 3,
		"question": "Which of the following bootstrap style of button makes the button size small?",
		"options": [
			".btn-lg",
			".btn-sm",
			".btn-xs",
			".btn-block"
		],
		"answer": ".btn-sm"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 4,
		"topicName": "BOOTSTRAP",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 4,
		"question": "Which of the following bootstrap styles are used to add a dropdown to a tab?",
		"options": [
			".nav, .nav-tabs, .menu",
			".nav, .nav-tabs, dropdown-.menu",
			".nav, .nav-pills, .dropdown",
			".nav, .nav-pills"
		],
		"answer": ".nav, .nav-tabs, dropdown-.menu"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 4,
		"topicName": "BOOTSTRAP",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 5,
		"question": "Which of the following bootstrap style can be used to to get different size items of .pagination?",
		"options": [
			".lg, .sm",
			".menu-lg, .menu-sm",
			" None",
			".pagination-lg, .pagination-sm"
		],
		"answer": ".pagination-lg, .pagination-sm"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 5,
		"topicName": "ANGULAR",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 1,
		"question": "Which of the following is correct about Angular 2 Components?",
		"options": [
			"AngularJS had a focus of Controllers but Angular 2 has changed the focus to having components over controllers.",
			"Components help to build the applications into many modules.",
			"This helps in better maintaining the application over a period of time.",
			"All of the above."
		],
		"answer": "All of the above."
	},
	{
		"topicId": 5,
		"topicName": "ANGULAR",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 2,
		"question": "Which of the following is true?",
		"options": [
			"Angular 2 Modules are used to create components which can be shared across the entire application.",
			"Angular 2 Metadata is used to create components which can be shared across the entire application.",
			"Angular 2 Services are used to create components which can be shared across the entire application.",
			"None of the above."
		],
		"answer": "Angular 2 Services are used to create components which can be shared across the entire application."
	},
	{
		"topicId": 5,
		"topicName": "ANGULAR",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 3,
		"question": "Which of the following is correct about Export Array in Angular 2 Modules?",
		"options": [
			"This is used to export components, directives, and pipes which can then be used in other modules.",
			"This is used to export services which can then be used in other services.",
			"Both of the above",
			"None of the above"
		],
		"answer": "This is used to export components, directives, and pipes which can then be used in other modules."
	},
	{
		"topicId": 5,
		"topicName": "ANGULAR",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 4,
		"question": "Which of the following is correct about Angular 2 Routing?",
		"options": [
			"Based on the option they choose, the required Angular Component will be rendered to the user.",
			"Routing helps in directing users to different pages based on the option they choose on the main page.",
			"Both of the above",
			"None of the above"
		],
		"answer": "Both of the above"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 5,
		"topicName": "ANGULAR",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 5,
		"question": " Which of the following is correct about package.json?",
		"options": [
			"There are two types of dependencies, first is the dependencies and then there are dev dependencies.",
			"The dev ones are required during the development process and the others are needed to run the application.",
			"Both of the above",
			"None of the above"
		],
		"answer": "Both of the above"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 6,
		"topicName": "NODE.JS",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 1,
		"question": "Which of following command starts a REPL session?",
		"options": [
			"node",
			"node start",
			"node repl",
			"node console"
		],
		"answer": "node"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 6,
		"topicName": "NODE.JS",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 2,
		"question": "Which of the following is true about package.json?",
		"options": [
			"package.json is present in the root directory of any Node application/module.",
			"package.json is used to define the properties of a package.",
			"package.json can be used to update dependencies of a Node application.",
			"All of the above."
		],
		"answer": "All of the above."
	},
	{
		"topicId": 6,
		"topicName": "NODE.JS",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 3,
		"question": "Which of the following is true about EventEmitter.emit property?",
		"options": [
			"emit property is used to locate an event handler.",
			"emit property is used to bind a function with the event.",
			"emit property is used to fire an event.",
			"None of the above"
		],
		"answer": "emit property is used to fire an event."
	},
	{
		"topicId": 6,
		"topicName": "NODE.JS",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 4,
		"question": "Which of the following is true about Chaining streams?",
		"options": [
			"Chanining is a mechanism to connect output of one stream to another stream and create a chain of multiple stream operations.",
			"Chanining is normally used with piping operations.",
			"Both of the above",
			"None of the above"
		],
		"answer": "Both of the above"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 6,
		"topicName": "NODE.JS",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 5,
		"question": "Which of the following module is required for exception handling in Node?",
		"options": [
			"web",
			"net",
			"domain",
			"error"
		],
		"answer": "domain"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 7,
		"topicName": "REACT.JS",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 1,
		"question": "ReactJS is developed by _____?",
		"options": [
			"Google",
			"Facebook",
			"Microsoft",
			"Oracle"
		],
		"answer": "Facebook"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 7,
		"topicName": "REACT.JS",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 2,
		"question": "ReactJS is an MVC based framework?",
		"options": [
			"True",
			"False",
			"XXX",
			"XXX"
		],
		"answer": ""
	},
	{
		"topicId": 7,
		"topicName": "REACT.JS",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 3,
		"question": "Which of the following concepts is/are key to ReactJS?",
		"options": [
			"Component-oriented design",
			"Event delegation model",
			"Both of the above",
			"None of the above"
		],
		"answer": "Both of the above"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 7,
		"topicName": "REACT.JS",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 4,
		"question": "ReactJS focuses on which of the following part when considering MVC?",
		"options": [
			"M (Model)",
			"V (View)",
			"C (Controller)",
			"None of the above"
		],
		"answer": "V (View)"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 7,
		"topicName": "REACT.JS",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 5,
		"question": "Which of the following API is a MUST for every ReactJS component?",
		"options": [
			"getInitialState",
			"render",
			"renderComponent",
			"All of the above"
		],
		"answer": "render"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 8,
		"topicName": "ANGULAR.JS",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 1,
		"question": "Which of the following is true about AngularJS expressions?",
		"options": [
			"Expressions are used to bind application data to html.",
			"Expressions are written inside double braces like {{ expression}}.",
			"Expressions behave in same way as ng-bind directives.",
			"All of the above."
		],
		"answer": "All of the above."
	},
	{
		"topicId": 8,
		"topicName": "ANGULAR.JS",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 2,
		"question": "What is controller in MVC?",
		"options": [
			"It is a software Code that stores the data.",
			"It is a software Code that renders the user interface.",
			"It is a software Code that controls the interactions between the Model and View.",
			"None of the above."
		],
		"answer": "It is a software Code that controls the interactions between the Model and View."
	},
	{
		"topicId": 8,
		"topicName": "ANGULAR.JS",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 3,
		"question": "Which of the following is true about $dirty flag?",
		"options": [
			"$dirty flag states that value has been changed.",
			"$dirty flag states that form has invalid data.",
			"Both of the above.",
			"None of the above."
		],
		"answer": "$dirty flag states that value has been changed."
	},
	{
		"topicId": 8,
		"topicName": "ANGULAR.JS",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 4,
		"question": "Is AngularJS extensible?",
		"options": [
			"True",
			"False",
			"XXX",
			"XXX"
		],
		"answer": "True"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 8,
		"topicName": "ANGULAR.JS",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 5,
		"question": "ng-app directive defines and links an AngularJS application to HTML.",
		"options": [
			"True",
			"False",
			"XXX",
			"XXX"
		],
		"answer": "True"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 9,
		"topicName": "TYPESCRIPT",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 1,
		"question": "What is extension for typescript file?",
		"options": [
			"abc.js",
			"abc.ts",
			"abc.tsc",
			"none of the above"
		],
		"answer": "abc.ts"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 9,
		"topicName": "TYPESCRIPT",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 2,
		"question": "Typescript is ___________ of JavaScript",
		"options": [
			"subset",
			"superset",
			"both",
			"none"
		],
		"answer": "superset"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 9,
		"topicName": "TYPESCRIPT",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 3,
		"question": "Typescript is developed under",
		"options": [
			"Google",
			"Facebook",
			"Microsoft",
			"Oracle"
		],
		"answer": "Microsoft"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 9,
		"topicName": "TYPESCRIPT",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 4,
		"question": "Typescript is a ________ language",
		"options": [
			"open source",
			"closed",
			"free",
			"a & c"
		],
		"answer": "open source"
	},
	{
		"topicId": 9,
		"topicName": "TYPESCRIPT",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 5,
		"question": "Typescript provides type checking at ",
		"options": [
			"run time",
			"compile time",
			"load time",
			"none of the above"
		],
		"answer": "compile time"
	},
		{
		"topicId": 10,
		"topicName": "JQUERY",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 1,
		"question": "Which built-in method removes the last element from an array and returns that element?",
		"options": [
			"last()",
			"get()",
			"pop()",
			"None of the above"
		],
		"answer": "pop()"
	},
		{
		"topicId": 10,
		"topicName": "JQUERY",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 2,
		"question": "Which of the following is correct about jQuery?",
		"options": [
			"The jQuery is very lightweight library - about 19KB in size ( Minified and gzipped ).",
			"The jQuery has cross-browser support, and works well in IE 6.0+, FF 2.0+, Safari 3.0+, Chrome and Opera 9.0+",
			"The jQuery supports CSS3 selectors and basic XPath syntax.",
			"All of the above."
		],
		"answer": "All of the above."
	},
		{
		"topicId": 10,
		"topicName": "JQUERY",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 3,
		"question": "Which of the following jQuery selector selects elements with the given element tag-name?",
		"options": [
			"$('tag-name')",
			"$('#tag-name')",
			"$('.tag-name')",
			"None of the above."
		],
		"answer": "$('tag-name')"
	},
		{
		"topicId": 10,
		"topicName": "JQUERY",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 4,
		"question": "Which of the following jQuery method remove all or the specified class(es) from the set of matched elements?",
		"options": [
			"removeClass( class )",
			"removeStyleClass( class )",
			"removeCSSClass( class )",
			"None of the above"
		],
		"answer": "removeClass( class )"
	},
		{
		"topicId": 10,
		"topicName": "JQUERY",
		"category": "difficult",
		"questionId": 5,
		"question": "Which of the following jQuery method filter out elements from a set of matched elements?",
		"options": [
			"filter( selector )",
			"setFilter( selector )",
			"putFilter( selector )",
			"None of the above."
		],
		"answer": "filter( selector )"
	}

]